Uh-oh.
South Park: Bigger, Longer & Uncut is a animation,
comedy film directed by Trey Parker.
In this feature film based on the hit animated series, the third graders of South Park sneak into an R-rated film by ultra-vulgar Canadian
television personalities Terrance and Phillip, and emerge with expanded vocabularies that leave their parents and teachers scandalized.
When outraged Americans try to censor the film, the controversy spirals into a call to wage war on Canada
and Terrance and Phillip end up on death row, with the kids their only hope of rescue.
Stan Marsh / Eric Cartman / Gregory / Satan / Mr. Garrison / Mr. Hat / Phillip Niles Argyle / Randy Marsh / Clyde Donovan / Tom - News Reporter / Midget In A Bikini / Canadian Ambassador /
Bombardiers / Mr. Mackey / Army General / Ned Gerblanski / Christophe - Ze Mole (or The Mole) / Big Gay Al (singing) / Adolf Hitler / Additional Voices (voice), played by Trey Parker.
Kyle Broflovski / Kenny McCormick / Saddam Hussein / Terrance Henry Stoot / Big Gay Al / Ticket Taker / Stuart McCormick
/ Jimbo Kearn / Gerald Broflovski / Butters Stotch / Additional Voices (voice), played by Matt Stone.
Liane Cartman / Sheila Broflovski / Sharon Marsh / Carol McCormick / Wendy Testaburger
/ Clitoris / Additional Voices (voice), played by Mary Kay Bergman.
Chef (voice), played by Isaac Hayes.
Ike Broflovski (voice), played by Jesse Brant Howell.
Ike Broflovski (voice), played by Anthony Cross-Thomas.
South Park: Bigger, Longer & Uncut is a 1999 American adult animated musical
black comedy film based on the animated sitcom South Park.
The film was directed by series creator Trey Parker, who co-wrote
with series co-creator Matt Stone and Pam Brady.
It stars Parker, Stone, Mary Kay Bergman, and Isaac Hayes, all of whom reprise their roles from
the series, with George Clooney, Eric Idle, and Mike Judge in supporting roles.
The plot follows Stan Marsh, Kyle Broflovski, Eric Cartman, and Kenny McCormick as they sneak into an R-rated
film starring the Canadian comedy duo Terrance and Phillip, after which they begin swearing.
When the consequent moral panic culminates in the United States declaring war on Canada, Stan, Kyle, and Cartman take it upon themselves to save
Terrance and Phillip from execution, while Kenny tries to prevent a prophecy involving Satan and Saddam Hussein's intent to conquer the world.
Primarily centered on themes of censorship and scapegoating, the film also parodies and satirizes the animated films of
the Disney Renaissance, musicals such as Les Misérables, and controversies surrounding the series itself.
The film also heavily satirizes the Motion Picture Association of America; during production, Parker and Stone disputed with
the MPAA, which returned the film multiple times with an NC-17 rating due to its frequent use of profanity.
The film's songs were written by Parker and Marc Shaiman,
the latter of whom composed the score.
South Park: Bigger, Longer & Uncut premiered at Grauman's Chinese Theatre on June 23, 1999, and was released
theatrically in the United States and Canada a week later by Paramount Pictures, with Warner Bros.
handling international distribution.
The film received critical acclaim from critics, who praised its
story, voice acting, soundtrack, humor and themes.
Produced on a $21 million budget, it grossed $83.1 million worldwide, making South Park: Bigger, Longer &
Uncut the highest-grossing R-rated animated film until 2016, when it was beaten by Sausage Party.
At the 72nd Academy Awards, the song "Blame Canada" was nominated for Best Original
Song, but it lost to Phil Collins' "You'll Be in My Heart" from Tarzan.
The film has since been considered one of the
greatest animated films of all time.
The film explores themes of hell, musical,
surrealism, world supremacy, visions of hell.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.